Hello everyone, welcome back to
another podcast here at English Pod.
My name is Marco and I'm Erica and today
We're looking at another one of our lessons
for English of the past decades
and this time It's the 1990s.
Well, you know, the 1990s is a little
easier for most of us to remember
Yeah, I guess it's a
little bit more recent.
We're gonna be looking at a lot
of language that is still used today
Most of these words and phrases are still
used today. So they're gonna be very useful
And you're gonna sound a lot more native.
Mm-hmm a lot cooler as well. Huh, right?
So before we get started
with this lesson, why
don't we take a look
at vocabulary preview?
vocabulary preview
We have two words we're going to hear in
the dialogue now the first one is a mall a
Mall. M-A-L-L mall. All right, so a
mall is basically short for shopping mall
Mm-hmm and a shopping
mall is a big building with many
stores inside right, so
it's like a shopping center
Mm-hmm and our last word
for vocabulary preview is gain
The gang the gang okay, so a
gang is a group of people, right?
Yeah, it's a group of people
you can call your friends the gang
We're gonna go out with the gang tonight.
Yeah. Now we sometimes hear this word
To have and it has a negative
meaning right right like street gang
Yeah, so people who are who fight and deal
drugs and all that sort of stuff, right?
So it can have a
negative and a positive
meaning so but it just
depends on how you use it
Yep, but in the dialogue
we'll hear it with the
positive meaning right
so that's all the words
We have for vocabulary preview.
Let's listen to this cool and hip
dialogue from the 1990s and we'll
come back later and explain some words
Hey for eyes, what's up,
man? How have you been not
bad just went to the mall
and picked up some junk
Check out my new Adidas those are dope
You are gonna be getting
mad props from the gang, man
Anyways, have you seen Betty lately?
Dude, don't even go there that girl
started trippin cuz I went to the
movies with Veronica the other day
I was like look you knew how
I was before you got with me
That's right. You're such a man.
Dude, there's Mad Max. Let's go say hi
Max was up. Are you
okay? You look like you
just saw a ghost. I got
an eff in English class
My life is over dude
You're over it. You need
to lay off the books for
a while and have some
fun. Come on. Let's bounce
Where are we going? Oh crap my dad's
gonna go post when he finds out about this
I'm gonna open the can
of what pass on you if
you don't come with me
right now. Okay, okay G
Well, it sounds like this guy's
got some problems at school, huh?
Yeah, he got an F on his
paper, but you always can count
on your friends to try and
cheer you up by doing something
Yeah, but they use some really
great phrases and vocabulary words
So why don't we look at those
now in language takeaway?
Language takeaway
All right on language takeaway we're
gonna be looking at five words and
Well, let's start with the first
one. So the guy was talking
about his really cool new
shoes his new Adidas, right?
Mm-hmm, and his friend
said those are dope dope dope
Okay, so it's pretty
easy to understand when
something is dope. It's
really awesome. It's cool
Yeah, it's great. Right.
It's great. So that's dope
Mm-hmm, and it's an adjective, right?
Mm-hmm
So his friend said those
are dope and he said
you're gonna be getting
mad props from the gang
Okay, so mad props mad props.
We can divide this word in two
So let's take a look at
the first part mad mad.
So we understand
that mad is angry, right?
Yeah, but it can also mean a lot, right?
Amazing. We're really
So if I say you have mad
skills, you're really good at
something or you can say
she has a mad amount of shoes
All right, so he's going to get mad
props now props is like respect or
Compliments. Yeah, so so his
shoes are so cool that he's going
to get a lot of respect
or a lot of compliments
from his friends Exactly
mad props mad props
So they started talking
about girls and he
mentioned that this
girl started trippin trippin
Trippin so to trip right as you notice
It's trippin. It doesn't
have the G at the
end which isn't really
grammatically correct
But that's kind of the way it's
pronounced. Yeah, we would
never say the G. Right. So if
somebody is trippin, they're
They're getting really upset.
They're getting really angry.
Right. They're causing trouble
So why don't we listen
to a couple of examples of
how we could use trippin
for different situations?
Example one
Leanne was trippin
because I got dirt on her car
Example two
Even though I apologize for calling
her fat genie was trippin all night
Example three
He sent me 43 text messages and call me
about 20 times that guy is trippin over me
Okay, so that's pretty clear
Trippin all right now
moving on to our next word
They wanted to go
somewhere and he said come
on. Let's bounce. Let's
bounce. I'm gonna bounce
Now a bounce basically means
Let's leave. Yeah, let's get out of here
But we might be more
familiar with this this word
as in like a ball right a
ball bounces off the floor
Exactly, so I guess it's
kind of the same you
kind of bounce off the
floor and leave that place
Yeah, let's bounce
Okay, so for a final word now this
guy who got a bad mark on his his paper
He was nervous about
what his dad would say right
right because his dad
was going to go postal
He said my dad is gonna
go postal to go postal
now if you go postal
it means you go crazy
Yeah, you really freak out you go you
get very angry. Yeah, like really angry
This word comes from the
90s because during a time it
was very common in the United
States that postal workers Melman
We're going a little bit crazy,
and you know, they started
shooting people and
delivering some strange packages
Well, I guess so people
who work in the post office
Maybe don't have the most exciting
jobs and that drives them a little crazy
Exactly that's what and but now
they have a a term named after them
All right, so why don't we listen to
our dialogue for the second time?
We're gonna slow it down a
little bit and then we'll come back
Hey, four eyes. What's up, man?
How have you been?
Not bad
Just went to the mall
and picked up some junk
Check out my new Adidas
Those are dope. You are gonna be
getting mad props from the gang, man.
Anyways, have you
seen better lately?
Dude, don't even go
there that girl started trippin
because I went to the movies
with Veronica the other day
I was like look you knew how
I was before you got with me
That's right. You're such a player man.
Dude, there's Mad Max. Let's go say hi
Max was uh
Are you okay?
You look like you just saw a ghost
I got an eff in English class.
My life is over
Dude, you're over it
You need to lay off the books
for a while and have some fun.
Come on. Let's bounce.
Where are we going?
Oh crap. My dad is gonna go
post when he finds out about this
I'm gonna open the can of what bass on
you if you don't come with me right now
Okay, okay jeez
Okay, so I think that was
a little easier to understand
You know, we've got a lot of pretty strange
words and phrases some interesting slang
Yeah, and I want to
take a look at this slang
now, so let's get started
with fluency builder
Fluency builder
Okay, so the guy
with the new shoes.
He asked his friends. Have
you seen Betty lately, right?
Right, and the his friend
replied don't even go there right?
He was like dude
don't even go there
Don't even go there. So what does he
mean when he says don't even go there?
He means don't talk about it.
I don't want to talk about it right?
Don't even touch that subject.
Don't even mention it right
So if somebody wants to talk
about a topic that you think
is sensitive or you don't want
to talk about us to say hey
Don't don't even go there. So Marco,
what do you think about the new tax law?
Don't even go there. I don't
even want to talk about politics.
Okay, so I think that's that's
a really actually quite helpful
phrase to avoid talking about
an uncomfortable subject, right?
So he said don't even go there
and he started talking about the
girl and she was trippin and
then he said something interesting
He said I was like look you knew
how I was before you got with me
Yeah, I really like
this phrase now.
I want to focus on the
first part. I was like I was like
I was like now you might hear
a lot of native English speakers
use these three words before
they start telling you what they said
So it's like saying I
said or I told him yep
So this actually is really common
especially with people under the age of 30
So why don't we hear a few more
examples of how it's used now example one
This guy caused a car
accident. I was like you idiot.
You can kill people
by driving like that
Example two and then I was like I hate
you and she was all like I hate you more
Example three
I told the teacher
that I didn't finish my
homework and he was
like I'll see you after school
So if you're telling a story
or you're maybe talking
to somebody and you
want to explain what you said
You can say I was like
hey, what are you doing?
And she was like what so
you can have an entire dialogue
based with I was like
she was like we were like
uh-huh Okay, so I was
like it's super super useful
So now our next word now
they they saw their friend
who got the bad marking in
school and the guy said dude
Get over it get over it.
So if somebody tells you to get over it
Stop worrying about it.
Okay, or stop thinking about it. All right
So if somebody is sad because maybe his
girlfriend broke up with him you would say
Get over it and stop thinking about it.
Go. It's in the past
Yeah, and you commonly
use this for um when
somebody is upset about
a small thing something
They shouldn't worry about.
Mm-hmm. Get over it. Yep. Now.
Why don't we go on to our final
word at the end of the dialogue?
They said I'm gonna open I can
of whoop ass. Okay, so to open
a can of whoop ass on somebody
to open a can of whoop ass
So again, let's break this
down before we explain
it. Okay, I think we have
to take one step back here
To whoop someone's ass is
to beat them up right right to
punch them and hurt them
right so to whoop somebody's ass
So if I open a can of whoop
ass, what does that mean?
It means you're
gonna beat them up
So it's just a funny very informal
way of saying like in this can I'm
gonna open it and I'm gonna start
hitting you or something like that
Some sort of small man is gonna jump out
of the can and start hitting you exactly
But it's never literal. It's not like
you're actually gonna beat somebody up
It's just kind of like a joke.
Yeah empty threat. Yeah
All right, so some really interesting
words and phrases in this dialogue
I think we should listen to it
for the last time and then we'll
come back and talk a little bit
more about this great decade
Paying for eyes. What's up, man.
How have you been?
Not bad. Just went to the mall and picked
up some joke. Check out my new Adidas
Those are dope. You are gonna be
getting mad props from the gang, man
Anyways, have you seen Betty lately?
Dude, don't even go there
That girl started trippin
because I went to the
movies with Veronica the
other day. I was like look
You knew how I was before you got with me.
That's right. You're such a player, man
Dude, there's mad max. Let's go say hi
Max was up. Are you
okay? You look like you
just saw a ghost. I
got an f in English class
My life is over dude. You're over it
You need to lay off the books
for a while and have some fun
Come on. Let's bounce.
Where are we going? Oh crap.
My dad's gonna go post
when he finds out about this
I'm gonna open the can of what bass on
you if you don't come with me right now
Okay, okay geez
Well, Marco in the dialogue.
I heard one of the guys say
what's up, but he said it in a
really strange way, didn't he?
Yeah, exactly. He said what's up
Okay, so what what's up with that?
So in the 90s it was popular
instead of saying what's up
You would just kind
of double BS and just
say what's up and then
it became very famous
With a TV commercial for
a certain beer and actually
I remember this commercial
during the the Super Bowl
They had this big commercial
where everyone was
saying what's up in this
really strange way, right?
It's still used today informally between
friends. You'll go ahead. Hey, what's up?
And what's that? Yeah, and you'll use it
Yeah, so that commercial
made it actually quite cool
and famous to talk like
that actually in Spanish pod
They have a show called gepasa,
which is like the translation of what's up
Oh, right. They start each show with like
saying gepasa, but it's exactly the same
So maybe it will become popular in Spanish.
Maybe, but I guess only
Time will tell. Yeah, that's right.
All right. So really cool stuff
And as we heard typical music
from the 90s and another interesting
thing was the nicknames for eyes
madmax very popular among young kids
So remember if you have any
questions about this language or
anything else about this lesson
come to our website at EnglishPod.com
Right, you can leave
all your questions and
comments there and we
hope to see you guys there
So thanks for listening and
until next time. Goodbye. Bye